Finding Aid for Sara Armstrong So papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sara Armstrong So papers 2006-2013
So, Sara Armstrong
0.1 linear feet and 831 MB (online)
2013145 Aa 2
Sara Armstrong So is a soldier with the Michigan Army National Guard. Papers include service summary and records, awards and commendations, written works, and visual materials (video and photographs files) relating to her military career and deployment in Afghanistan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Sara Armstrong So (donor no. 10954 ) in June 2013.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sara Armstrong So was born in Hillsdale, Michigan in 1986. She began her military career in Eastern Michigan University's ROTC program in 2004 on a full-ride scholarship. In 2006 she enlisted in the Michigan Army National Guard. She received her commission through Eastern Michigan University's ROTC program into the Michigan Army National Guard in 2008, and in May of 2009 she completed her Military Officer Basic Training course.
In July of 2011 Sara was called up to the HH210 Military Police Battalion and mobilized for deployment to Kuwait. In February of 2012 her orders were changed, and instead she was sent to Afghanistan for twelve months. She mobilized through camp Shelby, Mississippi to Western Afghanistan as a member of an SFAAT (Security Forces Advise and Assist Team). She was the first female soldier to ever be deployed to that location in Afghanistan.
During her time in Afghanistan she worked on a ten-person team which advised and assisted an Afghan border police battalion in logistics, operations, communication, and command and training issues. Her team also assisted at the border crossing point with Iran at the Islam Qala.
In February of 2013 Sara completed her deployment and returned to the United States where she took command of the 114th Military Police Company.
Materials in this collection comprise Sara Armstrong So's military service record with the Michigan Army National Guard. The collection will be of particular value for individuals interested in military activity in Afghanistan, women in the military, or daily-life images, videos and reflections from soldiers in Afghanistan (2012-2013).
Subjects:
Afghan War, 2001-; Michigan. National Guard.; So, Sara Armstrong.; United States--Armed Forces--Afghanistan.; United States. Army--Military life.; Women soldiers--United States.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Afghan War, 2001-; Afghans.; Aircraft.; Improvised Explosive Devices.; Michigan. National Guard.; Military camps.; Military life.; So, Sara Armstrong.; Soldiers.; United States--Armed forces--Afghanistan.; United States. Army--Military life.; Women soldiers.
Genre Terms:
Digital images.; Photographs.
- Biographical Materials
  The Biographical Materials series includes So's military records, awards, training certificates, and an autobiographical column describing her experiences in Afghanistan. The column was titled "Following Sara" and appeared in Simply Hers magazine.
  - Service Summary, 2013 (Box 1)
  - Service Records and Order, 2009-2013 (Box 1)
  - Certificates of Training, 2011-2013 (Box 1)
  - Awards and Commendations, 2013-2013 (Box 1)
  - "Following Sara" Column, 2012-2013 (Box 1)
    (Written by So)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series consist of two print photographs and many digital photographs. The photographs range from pre-mobilization activities to active duty in Afghanistan. Also included are two brief videos from So's deployment in Afghanistan.
  - Article photo featuring Sara So, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Military Identification Photo, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Camp Shelby (basic training and MP training), 2011-2012, .ZIP file
  - Pre-Mobilization, 2012, .ZIP file
  - Afghanistan Tour of Duty (So with members of her team, Afghan border police battalion, and Afghan children, as well as images of landscapes, daily activities, and military aircraft), 2012-2013, .ZIP file
  - Promotion, 2012, .ZIP file
  - Afghanistan Videos (supply drop-off from a military aircraft and detonation of an IED), 2012-2013, .ZIP file